Guide to the New Dramatists Records
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Script Library, 1931-1985; Series I; 39.17; (32 boxes)
  - Wilson, Lanford
    - Fifth of July, 1978 (Box 30)
    - Lemon Sky (Manuscript), undated (Box 30)
    - Lemon Sky (Published), 1970 (Box 30)
    - Serenading Louie, 1984 (Box 30)
    - Summer and Smoke (opera), undated (Box 30)
  - Winters, Marian
    - All is Bright, undated (Box 30)
    - Breadwinner, undated (Box 30)
    - E. R., undated (Box 30)
    - Getting There Soon, undated (Box 30)
    - The Tour, undated (Box 30)
  - Wolfson, John
    - April, undated (Box 30)
    - The Blood of the Caesars, 1973 (Box 31)
    - Brother Lorenzo, 1964 (Box 31)
    - Call Off the Hunt, undated (Box 31)
    - The Calm before the Bomb, 1967 (Box 31)
    - Casanova (musical), 1977 (Box 31)
    - Deep Six the Briefcase, 1973 (Box 31)
    - Flight 901, 1970 (Box 31)
    - The Inn at Lydda, 1973 (Box 31)
    - Jimmy Paradise, 1964 (Box 31)
    - The Love-Death of Madam Babinsky, 1972 (Box 31)
    - A Midsummer Night's Trip, 1967 (Box 31)
    - Mother Hump, 1964 (Box 31)
    - Poison Ivy, 1963 (Box 31)
    - Syndrome Shift, 1966 (Box 31)
  - Wren, Scott Christopher
    - Einstein in Ixtlan, 1981 (Box 31)
  - Wright, Elizabeth McFadden
    - The Wolf Has Eaten Grandmother, undated (Box 31)
  - Wyman, Joel
    - The Old Crow Said, undated (Box 31)
  - Yalowitz, Dena Reichel
    - Jacob Cohen, 1953 Jan 12 (Box 31)
    - The Torque, 1953 Aug 17 (Box 31)
  - Yarema, Neil
    - Bad News (screenplay), undated (Box 31)
    - End Not My Song Before I Sing, undated (Box 31)
    - A Mad Theatre for Madmen, undated (Box 31)
    - The Quiet Weekend of Delbert Moss (screenplay), 1971 Feb (Box 31)
    - Rampart Street (musical), undated (Box 31)
    - Route 40, undated (Box 31)
    - "Say, What?", undated (Box 31)
    - Smartass, undated (Box 32)
    - Travelin' West (screenplay), undated (Box 32)
  - Yaven, Mitchell
    - Bystanders, 1979 (Box 32)
    - Koetfire, undated (Box 32)
  - Yellen, Sherman
    - Rex (musical), undated (Box 32)
    - Time Out of Marble, undated (Box 32)
- Administrative Files, 1949-1996; Series II; 114.58; (100 boxes) + 12 broadside folders
  Conditions Governing Access
  Box 128: Restricted until 2050. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
  Box 129 (audiocassettes): Use of originals is restricted. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  Boxes 130-132 (reel-to-reel tapes): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  The records include administrative correspondence, application files, financial and fund-raising records, internal reports, audio recordings and transcripts of guest lectures and craft discussions, audio recordings of board meetings and play readings, photographs, scrapbooks holding clippings about the organization, artwork and production materials for New Dramatists newsletters and publications, and other files related to the group's management and activities. Audiovisual materials, group of doodles created by theatre celebrities, and a set of autographed sign-in boards from the New Dramatists' annual spring luncheons are filed at the end of the series. The records primarily date from the organization's founding in 1949 through the 1988-1989 season.
  The arrangement of the files in this series reflects the order in which the material was packed up in the New Dramatists offices in 1998; most of the files are roughly in chronological order.
  - Lectures
    - Anderson, Robert
      - Lecture number 1, undated (Box 33)
      - Lecture number 2, undated (Box 33)
      - Lecture number 3 (part II), undated (Box 33)
    - Baker, Paul
      - Golden Theatre, 1960 April 26 (Box 33)
    - Beaufort, John
      - Lecture for the New Dramatists' Committee, undated (Box 33)
    - Bentley, Eric
      - Helen Hayes Theatre, 1958 December 2 (Box 33)
      - Golden Theatre, 1960 May 19 (Box 33)
    - Burrows, Abe
      - Morosco Theatre (2 copies), 1959 May 21 (Box 33)
    - Burrows, Abe, Crouse, Russel and Lindsay, Howard
      - A New Dramatists craft discussion, 1957 January 21 (Box 33)
    - Canfield, F. Curtis
      - The Irish Theatre, 1959 October 23 (Box 33)
    - Chapman, Robert
      - Golden Theatre, 1960 February 18 (Box 33)
    - Clurman, Harold
      - Helen Hayes Theatre, Phoenix Theatre, Coronet Theatre, 1958-1959, undated (Box 33)
    - Drayton, Mary
      - A New Dramatists craft discussion, 1956 March 5 (Box 33)
    - Foon, Dennis
      - Zaydok, 1988 May 23 (Box 33)
    - Ferguson, Francis
      - Morosco Theatre, 1959 January 6 (Box 33)
    - Gassner, John
      - Morosco Theatre, 1958, 1959 (Box 33)
    - Hart, Moss
      - A New Dramatists Craft Discussion (2 copies), 1956 October 4 (Box 33)
      - Golden Theatre, 1959 December 3 (Box 33)
    - Hayward, Leland
      - Belasco Theatre, 1961 January 31 (Box 33)
    - Hellman, Lillian
      - Coronet Theatre (2 copies), 1958 November 18 (Box 33)
    - Houghton, Norris
      - Morosco Theatre, 1959 January 27 (Box 33)
    - Kazan, Elia
      - A New Dramatists craft discussion (2 copies), 1955 November 7 (Box 33)
      - A New Dramatists craft discussion, 1957 April 9 (Box 33)
    - Kramm, Joseph
      - A New Dramatists craft discussion, 1957 February 27 (Box 33)
    - Kronenberger
      - The Restoration, undated (Box 33)
    - Lindsay, Howard
      - Tennessee Williams and some New Dramatists, 1951 February 8 (Box 33)
      - Belasco Theatre, 1961 January 31 (Box 33)
    - Logan, Joshua
      - Joshua Logan and some New Dramatists, undated (Box 33)
      - Craft discussion with New Dramatists (2 copies), undated (Box 33)
    - Mielziner, Jo
      - Morosco Theatre, 1958 February 12 (Box 33)
    - Miller, Arthur
      - A New Dramatists craft discussion, 1956 February 27 (Box 33)
    - St. Denis, Michel
      - Helen Hayes Theatre (2 copies), 1959 March 31 (Box 33)
      - Morosco Theatre (3 copies), 1959 November 19 (Box 33)
    - Schneider, Alan
      - Golden Theatre, 1960 March 29 (Box 33)
    - Van Druten, John
      - Speech (2 complete copies and 1 partial copy), undated (Box 33)
    - Whitehead, Robert
      - Golden Theatre, undated (Box 33)
    - Young, Stark
      - Morosco Theatre (2 copies), 1959 May 7 (Box 33)
  - Luncheon invitation list, undated (Box 34)
  - New Dramatists contact information, undated (Box 34)
  - Bank deposit forms, undated (Box 34)
  - Sardi's luncheon extra lists, April 14 (Box 34)
  - Correspondence literary agents committee, undated (Box 34)
  - Barlow, Anna Marie, undated (Box 34)
  - Membership, undated (Box 34)
  - Correspondence, 1966 June (Box 34)
  - Literary Agents Committee
    - Boettcher, Henry, 1962 (Box 34)
    - Brown, Kay, 1962 (Box 34)
    - Cohen, Janet, 1961-1962 (Box 34)
    - Degener, Claire, 1962 (Box 34)
    - Freedman, Harold, 1961-1962 (Box 34)
    - Harvey, Helen, 1961-1962 (Box 34)
    - Howell, Miriam, 1961-1962 (Box 34)
    - Kroll, Lucy, 1961-1962 (Box 34)
    - McCall, Monica, 1961-1962 (Box 34)
    - Phelps, Jack, 1962 (Box 34)
    - Roberts, Flora, 1961-1962 (Box 34)
    - Roberts, Janet, 1961-1962 (Box 34)
    - Salisbury, Leah, 1961-1962 (Box 34)
    - Schulberg, Mrs. Budd, 1961-1962 (Box 34)
    - Williams, Annie Laurie, 1961-1962 (Box 34)
  - Thank you letters to producers, 1963 (Box 34)
  - Correspondence (general), 1962 (Box 34)
  - Workshop letters- actors, 1952-1954 (Box 34)
  - Macy's, 1973 (Box 34)
  - Correspondence and budget information, undated (Box 34)
  - Insurance- claims, etc., undated (Box 34)
  - Tax exemption- federal and state annual reports, undated (Box 34)
  - Luncheons, 1963-1982; 6 (Box 35)
  - New York State Council on the Arts, 1975-1976 (Box 35)
  - O'Neill Luncheon, 1972 November 14 (Box 35)
  - A Little Night Music, undated (Box 35)
  - Fund raising contributions, undated (Box 35)
  - Lecture pitch- fund raising, undated (Box 35)
  - Fund raising reports, 1974 (Box 35)
  - Lists for the 1968 campaign, undated (Box 35)
  - Letters with contributions, 1962 (Box 35)
  - Grant information, 1983 (Box 35)
  - Industry- Backstage fund raising luncheon, 1961 February 9 (Box 35)
  - Benefit performance of "Coco", 1969 November 13 (Box 35)
  - Benefit performance of "The Lion in Winter", 1968 November 3 (Box 35)
  - Luncheon follow-up, 1963 (Box 35)
  - Industry drive, 1972 (Box 35)
  - Fund raising drive, 1978 (Box 35)
  - Benefit performance of "On the Town", 1971 October 28 (Box 35)
  - Tony parties, undated (Box 35)
  - Industry drive (past), undated (Box 35)
  - Benefit performance of "Mack and Mabel", 1974 October 22 (Box 35)
  - Fund for the Republic material, undated (Box 35)
  - Foundations contributing more than ten thousand dollars to the performing arts, 1959-1960 (Box 35)
  - Ford Foundation programs, 1957-1958 (Box 36)
  - Rockefeller reports, 1954 (Box 36)
  - Benefit preview of "The Rothschilds", 1970 October 7; 3 (Box 36)
  - Fund raising reports, 1974-1976 (Box 36)
  - Industry drive, 1985 June 30 (Box 36)
  - Fund raising reports, 1969-1974 (Box 36)
  - Parties, 1951-1952 (Box 36)
  - Frank, Mary K. (gift and party), 1969 May 12 (Box 36)
  - Luncheon, 1969 (Box 36)
  - Benefit performance of "Coco", 1969 (Box 36)
  - Letters from the 1970 campaign (Box 36)
  - Ford Foundation
    - Correspondence, undated (Box 36)
    - Bills, undated (Box 36)
    - Director-observer project, 1958 June (Box 36)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, undated (Box 36)
    - Ford fund presentation, undated (Box 36)
  - Foundation presentation, undated (Box 36)
  - Fund raising drive, 1961-1962 (Box 36)
  - List of contributors interested in playwrights and new plays, undated (Box 36)
  - Lorelei advertisement in Variety, 1973 May 16 (Box 36)
  - Benefit committee, 1974 (Box 36)
  - Industry drive, 1975 (Box 36)
  - Lists, undated (Box 36)
  - Fund raising results, 1961 (Box 36)
  - Industry drive letter, 1962-1966 (Box 36)
  - An hour with the New Dramatists, 1971 (Box 36)
  - Benefit performance of "The Lion in Winter", undated (Box 36)
  - Theatre benefit supper arrangements, 1974 October (Box 37)
  - Theatre benefit program, 1974 October (Box 37)
  - Freddy Lazarus contributors, 1987 (Box 37)
  - "The Warm Peninsula" Benefit, 1959 (Box 37)
  - Benefit, 1959 (Box 37)
  - Matching gifts, undated (Box 37)
  - Fund-raising reports, 1971-1975 (Box 37)
  - Theatre benefit correspondence, 1974 October (Box 37)
  - Theatre benefit committee lists, 1974 October (Box 37)
  - Theatre benefit printed materials, 1974 October (Box 37)
  - New York State Council on the Arts, 1976-1977 (Box 37)
  - National Endowment for the Arts, 1969-1976; 9 (Box 37)
  - Solicitation, 1959 December (Box 37)
  - Luncheons, 1979-1980; 4 (Box 37)
  - Luncheon categories, 1971 (Box 37)
  - Luncheon program, 1966 (Box 37)
  - Fund for the Republic presentation, 1959 September (Box 37)
  - Fund for the Republic correspondence, undated (Box 37)
  - Ford and Rockefeller financial reports (Box 37)
  - Rockefeller fund grant (Box 37)
  - Theatre Launching, 1965 November (Box 37)
  - Theatre Guild mailing, undated (Box 37)
  - Film showing- women's committee, 1963 January 22 (Box 37)
  - Financial Records
    - Monthly reports, 1984 June 30 (Box 38)
    - Mortgage & loan (Box 38)
    - Social security mix-up, 1982-1983 (Box 38)
    - NY telephone deposit, 1983 (Box 38)
    - Payroll taxes, 1979-1981 (Box 38)
    - Petro Fuel, 1981 (Box 38)
    - Insurance
      - State insurance fund, 1984 (Box 38)
      - De Witt Stern, Gutmann & Co., Inc., 1983 (Box 38)
      - Umbrella and excess liability, 1980-1981 (Box 38)
      - Workmen's compensation, 1980-1984 (Box 38)
      - Disability, 1980-1983 (Box 38)
      - Comprehensive business, 1980-1984 (Box 38)
      - General, 1977-1984; 2 (Box 38)
    - Seaman's Bank for Savings, 1977-1980 (Box 38)
    - Stock, 1969-1981 (Box 38)
    - 6 month statement/ balance sheets, 1983 (Box 38)
    - Theft, 1983 July 24 (Box 38)
    - TDF loan, 1981-1982 (Box 38)
    - Treasury bills, 1981-1982 (Box 38)
    - Inheritances, 1982 (Box 38)
    - Form 2758, 1980-1981 (Box 38)
    - General cinema stock, 1983-1984 (Box 38)
    - 990 forms & tax exempt forms, 1988 (Box 38)
    - Form 990, 1971 (Box 38)
    - Financial information, undated (Box 38)
    - Form 497- charities registration, 1971-1983 (Box 38)
    - Con Edison deposit, 1980-1984 (Box 38)
    - Citibank, 1984; 2 (Box 38)
    - Chemical Bank, 1981 (Box 38)
    - Census, 1982 (Box 38)
    - Building appraisal, 1980-1984 (Box 38)
    - Activities, 1973-1974 (Box 38)
    - Loan sources, undated (Box 38)
    - Administrative fund raising, 1984 (Box 38)
    - Artist services, 1982-1984 (Box 38)
    - Literary services department, 1984 (Box 38)
    - Program department, 1983-1984 (Box 38)
    - Arnold Weissberger - Tony Awards, 1970-1971 (Box 38)
    - Benefit performances, 1974 (Box 38)
    - Unions, undated (Box 38)
    - Swann's Way, 1969 (Box 38)
    - Benefit lists, 1968-1971 (Box 38)
    - Entertainers lists & letters, 1972 (Box 38)
    - Fund raising, 1961-1974 (Box 38)
    - American Metal Climax Foundation, Inc., 1973 (Box 38)
    - Contributions (board, etc.), 1979-1983 (Box 38)
    - Play of the Month Guild - fund raising, 1961 (Box 38)
    - Benefit performance of "The Warm Peninsula", 1951-1959 (Box 38)
    - Luncheon, 1961 April 14 (Box 38)
    - Invitation list, undated (Box 38)
    - Cocktail party, 1962 March 16 (Box 38)
    - Monthly taxes - federal, state, and city, 1971; 3 (Box 39)
    - New York City real estate taxes, 1974 (Box 39)
    - Monthly financial summaries, 1971-1972 (Box 39)
    - Tax exemption, undated (Box 39)
    - Insurance, 1957-1958 (Box 39)
    - Financial statement, 1957-1958 (Box 39)
    - Circulation, 1957-1958 (Box 39)
    - Blue Cross, 1957 (Box 39)
    - Irving Trust Company, 1960-1962 (Box 39)
    - Chase Manhattan Bank- Play of the Month Club, 1967 June 1 (Box 39)
    - New York state taxes, 1960-1970 (Box 39)
    - New York income taxes, 1966-1970 (Box 39)
    - Paid bills, 1970 (Box 39)
    - Rockefeller correspondence, 1954 (Box 39)
    - Post office paper, undated (Box 39)
    - Monthly financial statements, 1976 (Box 39)
    - Yearly budgets, 1969-1975 (Box 39)
    - Monthly financial reports, 1973 (Box 39)
    - Finances- budgets, 1951-1954 (Box 39)
    - New Dramatists' lending fund (Society of Author's Representatives), 1953 (Box 39)
    - Cancelled checks, 1958 (Box 39)
    - General account, 1970 (Box 39)
    - Cancelled checks, 1957-1958 (Box 39)
    - Petty cash, 1957-1958 (Box 39)
    - Receipts, 1957-1958 (Box 39)
    - U.S. Internal Revenue- 990-A, 1957 (Box 39)
    - Employer's quarterly federal tax return, 1957-1958; 2 (Box 39)
    - New play circulation (bank statements), 1955; 2 (Box 39)
    - Deposits, 1957-1958 (Box 39)
    - Manager's signatory to basic agreement, 1946 (Box 40)
    - Plan for playwrights, undated (Box 40)
    - Admission, 1950-1978 (Box 40)
    - Procedures, 1950's (Box 40)
    - Form letters, 1949-1951 (Box 40)
    - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 40)
    - Program Reports, undated (Box 40)
    - "The Lion and the Unicorn", 1952 (Box 40)
    - "The Trouble-Makers", 1952 (Box 40)
    - Script Reports, 1950-1951 (Box 40)
    - Workshop correspondence, 1951 (Box 40)
    - Budgets, 1949-1951 (Box 40)
    - Probationary group, undated (Box 40)
    - Starfish, 1952 (Box 40)
    - Foundations, undated (Box 40)
    - Correspondence with the Stage Manager's Club, 1950 (Box 40)
    - National drama fraternities and sororities almanac, 1951 (Box 40)
    - "Palm Garden", 1952 (Box 40)
    - Circulation, undated (Box 40)
    - Forms, 1951-1952 (Box 40)
    - Office expenses - NDC account, 1952 (Box 40)
    - Actors, undated (Box 40)
    - Golden, John - correspondence, 1951-1957 (Box 40)
    - Activities reports to Rockefeller Foundation, undated (Box 40)
    - N. D. C. properties, 1953 (Box 40)
    - Contribution, before 1955 (Box 40)
    - Theatre collection, undated (Box 40)
    - Rehearsed reading of "Southern Comfort", 1953 (Box 40)
    - Staged showing of "Lisa and the Lord", 1953 (Box 40)
    - "Does the Hawk Fly", undated (Box 40)
    - "Half the World is a Bride", 1953 (Box 40)
    - "Day of Grace", 1953 (Box 40)
    - Publicity clippings, undated (Box 40)
    - "The Long Whistle", undated (Box 40)
    - Dramatists Guild correspondence, up to 1953 (Box 40)
    - Transcriptions from tapes, undated (Box 40)
    - Fund-raising certificates, 1953 (Box 40)
    - Lindsay, Howard, 1951-1954 (Box 40)
    - Edison Voicewriter advertisement, undated (Box 40)
    - Activities report on the plan for playwrights, 1953-1954 (Box 40)
    - Staged Reading of "Lisa and the Lord", 1953 (Box 40)
    - "Red Sky at Morning", 1953 (Box 40)
    - "Tiger!", 1953 (Box 40)
    - "Speak with Demons", 1953 (Box 40)
    - "The Midnight Cry", 1953 (Box 40)
    - Financial statement (3 copies), 1953 May 31 (Box 40)
    - "Denny Malone", 1953 (Box 40)
    - Rehearsed reading of "Happy Ending", 1953 (Box 40)
    - Rehearsed reading of "The Bride Cried", 1953 (Box 40)
    - "Citizen", 1953 (Box 40)
    - Correspondence from O'Harra, Michaela, 1954 (Box 40)
    - Children's consent forms, undated (Box 40)
    - Financial Report, 1953-1954 (Box 40)
    - "The White Steeple", 1954 (Box 40)
    - Workshop maintenance, 1954-1955 (Box 40)
    - Petty cash, 1954-1955 (Box 40)
    - Production observations, 1952-1955 (Box 40)
    - Craft discussion, 1956 (Box 40)
    - Completed sounding panels, 1954 (Box 40)
    - "God had Seven Days", 1954 (Box 40)
    - Garfunkel, Benjamin J., 1954 (Box 40)
    - Membership corporation law section 46 annual report, 1954-1955 (Box 40)
    - "The Fish are Dying in the Sea", 1954 (Box 41)
    - "Love in an Album", 1954 (Box 41)
    - "The Coffee Bean", 1954 (Box 41)
    - Second rehearsed reading of "The World is Yours", 1954 (Box 41)
    - "East Side Gladiator", 1954 (Box 41)
    - "A Neighborhood Affair", 1954 May (Box 41)
    - "The Lexington Avenue Entrance", 1954 (Box 41)
    - Rehearsed Reading "There's Always Bosc", 1955 June (Box 41)
    - "The Illegitimist", 1959 (Box 41)
    - Elinor Morgenthau New Dramatists workshop financial statement (5 copies), 1954 May 31 (Box 41)
    - "The Outside World", 1954 (Box 41)
    - "Ceremony of Innocence", 1954 (Box 41)
    - Circulation report, ozalid, 1954-1955 (Box 41)
    - "Willie's Fall", undated (Box 41)
    - "The Princess Incident", undated (Box 41)
    - Elinor Morgenthau New Dramatists workshop account, 1954 (Box 41)
    - Carl Zimmerle "Sea, Salt, and Sand", 1954 (Box 41)
    - Proposals for workshop activities and Partisan Review, 1954 (Box 41)
    - List of New Dramatists plays, undated (Box 41)
    - Drama Guild lists, 1954 (Box 41)
    - Workshop background information, undated (Box 41)
    - Rockefeller Foundation, 1954 (Box 41)
    - General correspondence, 1954 (Box 41)
    - Thornton Wilder letter, 1957 April 2 (Box 41)
    - Press releases, undated (Box 41)
    - Producers correspondence, 1954 (Box 41)
    - Publicity, 1955 (Box 41)
    - Second Rehearsed Reading of "Lexington Avenue Entrance", 1955 (Box 41)
    - Complete revised proposal, ozalid, 1955-1956 (Box 41)
    - Second circulation bulletin, undated (Box 41)
    - New York State Department of Social Welfare, undated (Box 41)
    - First rehearsed reading of "The Moon is a Clock", 1955 (Box 41)
    - "The Gift of Mountains", undated (Box 41)
    - Miscellaneous workshop papers, undated (Box 41)
    - Financial report (includes photographs), 1955-1956 (Box 41)
    - Council meetings, 1955-1957 (Box 41)
    - Newsletters, 1955; 2 (Box 41)
    - Special documents, 1956 (Box 41)
    - Second rehearsed reading of "Suspicious People", 1955; 2 (Box 41)
    - "Cold Christmas", 1955; 2 (Box 41)
    - Rehearsed reading of "Dog Days in Autumn", undated (Box 41)
    - "Friday's Child", 1955 (Box 41)
    - "O'Malley the Duck", 1955 (Box 41)
    - "Lydia Pinkham", undated (Box 41)
    - "The Castle", 1955 (Box 41)
    - "Sailing to Byzantium", 1955 (Box 41)
    - "The World is Yours", 1955 (Box 41)
    - Rehearsed reading of "The Old Crow Said", 1955 (Box 41)
    - "This Here Emerson", 1955; 2 (Box 41)
    - "Bad Angels", 1955 (Box 41)
    - New Dramatists Committee, Inc. and Elinor Morgenthau - New Dramatists workshop, 1955 May 31 (Box 41)
    - Blue Cross- Blue Shield information, 1955 (Box 41)
    - Form letters- extra copies, 1955-1956 (Box 41)
    - General correspondence, 1955-1956 (Box 41)
    - Financial report, 1955-1956 (Box 41)
    - Recommended plays- evaluations and synopses, undated (Box 42)
    - Forms, 1955-1956 (Box 42)
    - Proposals, 1955-1956 (Box 42)
    - New Dramatists Committee, Inc. and Elinor Morgenthau - New Dramatists workshop, 1956 May 31 (Box 42)
    - Pending, undated (Box 42)
    - Craft discussion with Howard Bay, typescript first draft, undated (Box 42)
    - First rehearsed reading of "Dark Odyssey", 1957 (Box 42)
    - Production observation, 1956-1957 (Box 42)
    - First rehearsed reading of "The Velvet Cage", undated (Box 42)
    - Special account, 1956 (Box 42)
    - Statements and checks, 1956 (Box 42)
    - First rehearsed reading of "Take the Devil's Hand", 1956 (Box 42)
    - Correspondence, New Dramatists board of directors, 1956-1959 (Box 42)
    - First rehearsed reading of "A Father and Everything", 1956 (Box 42)
    - First rehearsed reading of "Abracadabra", 1956 (Box 42)
    - VIP list, undated (Box 42)
    - First rehearsed reading of "An Owl in a Chinaberry Tree", undated (Box 42)
    - Members bulletins, 1955-1956 (Box 42)
    - "Birds Still Ring", 1956 (Box 42)
    - First rehearsed reading of "The China Dog", 1956 (Box 42)
    - First rehearsed reading of "The Small Woman", 1956 (Box 42)
    - Rockefeller Foundation - budget, etc., 1958; 2 (Box 42)
    - Chamberlain, undated (Box 42)
    - General correspondence, 1956-1957 (Box 42)
    - Telegrams, 1956 (Box 42)
    - Treasurers report, 1956-1957 (Box 42)
    - Second rehearsed reading of "The Queens Pawn", 1956 (Box 42)
    - Invitation lists for rehearsed readings, 1956 (Box 42)
    - Workshop prospectus, undated (Box 42)
    - Completed readings, 1956-1957 (Box 42)
    - Recommended plays - Ford Foundation, 1956 (Box 42)
    - Rockefeller Foundation- playwright observer - Comorthoon, James, undated (Box 42)
    - "Time is a Thief", 1956 (Box 42)
    - First rehearsed reading of "The Deal", undated (Box 42)
    - "God is a Clown" (not completed), undated (Box 42)
    - Faith for Today, undated (Box 42)
    - Publicity, 1955-1956 (Box 42)
    - Fund for the Republic grant application, 1956 (Box 42)
    - New Dramatists Committee, Inc. and Elinor Morgenthau - New Dramatists workshop, 1957 May 31 (Box 42)
    - Ford Foundation material, 1957 (Box 42)
    - Petty cash, 1956-1957 (Box 42)
    - Proposals, 1957 (Box 42)
    - Morgenthau family finances, undated (Box 42)
    - Statements and checks, 1956-1957 (Box 42)
    - Council meetings, 1957-1958 (Box 42)
    - Rockefeller Foundation grant application, 1957 (Box 42)
    - Completed panels, 1955-1956 (Box 42)
    - Completed panels, 1957-1958 (Box 43)
    - First rehearsed reading of "The Johnson House", undated (Box 43)
    - First rehearsed reading of "Carnation, Lily, Lily, Rose", undated (Box 43)
    - Ticket Requests, 1957-1958 (Box 43)
    - Thank you notes, 1957-1958 (Box 43)
    - Theatre admissions, 1957-1958 (Box 43)
    - Rehearsed reading of the third act of "Taffy", 1957-1958 (Box 43)
    - Rehearsed reading of "The Great Git-away", 1957-1958 (Box 43)
    - First rehearsed reading of "The Little Gondola", 1957 (Box 43)
    - First rehearsed reading of "The Boy on the Beach", 1957 (Box 43)
    - First rehearsed reading of "A Coin to Cross Acheron", undated (Box 43)